Inventory of the Middletown Manuscripts Collection, 1668 - 1937
Middletown Manuscripts Collection, 1668 - 1937
  - Indian Localities around Portland, Connecticut and Lists of Indian Relics Collected in that Vicinity by Charles H. Neff (Box 2)
    - Page 8
      Several Indian relics have been found on a plowed lot belonging to Horace Wilcox bordering the meadow south of the lower wougouk meadow drain. A plowed piece of ground belonging to Nelson Shepherd a short distance south of the brook leading to the upper wougouk meadow drain and bordering the east side of the wougouk meadows is a fair collecting ground. Several Indian relics have been found on the Charles Abbey farm at Gildersleeve. There was once an Indian village off the John Worthington farm.
    - Page 9
      Several arrowheads were found during the summer of 1884 on a plowed field bordering the Pacoreset Road on the Joseph Hall farm. A few Indian relics have been found in the sands about Brush pond meadows.
    - Page 10
      Quite a number of Indian relics have been found on plowed ground in the vicinity of a brook running through the John McLeave farm at Pacouset in the vicinity of the Catholic Cemetery and back of old farm house. There was once an Indian Settlement along the bank of the Connecticut River between Pacouset Drain and Bodkin Rock at the head of the straits. A piece of ground was plowed in the fall of 1890 at the Land Hill Swamp.
    - Page 11
      A few Indian relics have been found on plowed ground bordering the north side of the Chester Hurlbut cranberry marsh at Bucktown, Portland, Conn. Quite a number of arrowheads have been picked up from time to time on plowed ground bordering Coxes Brook on the Samuel Hurlbut farm.
    - Page 15: Indian Localities about Glastonbury, Conn.
      Found a fine collecting ground in the fall of 1884 between the Rocky Hill Ferry Road and the road leading to the Steamboat dock. A large Indian village was once at Red Hill Couth Glastonbury just north of Roaring Brook and but a shout distance back from the Connecticut River.
    - Page 16
      From Red Hill up through Glastonbury many Indian relics can be found. Araubuc North Glastonbury, Conn is a good collecting locality.
    - Page 17
      A piece of plowed ground bordering the Roaring Brook at South Glastonbury, Conn directly across from the Charles Hall fields and mill and not far from the stone bridge is a fairly good collecting ground.
    - Page 19: Indian Localities about Rocky Hill, Conn.
      A few Indian relics have been found on the Connecticut River shore at Lower Rocky Hill directly opposite Toyoutown about the vicinity of where a brook empties in the Connecticut River.
    - Page 21: Indian Localities about Cromwell, Conn.
      There was once an Indian settlement on the bank of the Connecticut River at North Cromwell, Conn. but a short distance above the Breakwater and extending for several rods along the shore. A large number of Indian relics have been found on the Cromwell shore north of brook leading into the Connecticut River directly across from Indian Hill, Portland.
    - Page 22
      Found several Indian relics on what is known as the Neck. A few Indian relics have been found along the Connecticut River shore from the head of Willow Island down to the entrance to Little River Cromwell, Conn.
    - Page 23
      Found several Indian relics on a piece of ground that was plowed in the fall of 1895 close by the Henry Hall barn on Fir Neck Little River Meadows.
    - Page 26: Indian Localities about Fairfield, Conn.
      Several Indian relics have been found at a place known as the Point. Several Indian relics have been found on plowed ground bordering the Little River Meadows south of Tuttles Brickyard at what is called Gilberts Point.
    - Page 29: Indian Localities about Middletown, Conn.
      There was once a large Indian village on the of the Middletown Branch Railroad near the West River Bridge. A large factory is now built year 1897 on the old Indian village site at what for years was known as the Griffin Trotting Park near the West River bridge.
    - Page 31: Indian Localities about Maromas, Conn.
      Several Indian relics have been found on the farm of Henry Durham on land but a short distance back from the Connecticut River. Found a few Indian relics on the Connecticut River shore at Maromas opposite the Middle Haddam Landing and back of the Island.
    - Page 37: Indian Localities about Maromas, Conn.
      Indian Relics from various localities in collection.
    - Page 44
      Collected several Indian relics before the year 1885 but kept no record of them.
    - Page 45: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1885
    - Page 49: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1886
    - Page 53: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1887
    - Page 57: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1888
    - Page 63: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1889
    - Page 69: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1890
    - Page 73: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1891
    - Page 79: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1892
    - Page 85: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1893
    - Page 89: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1894
    - Page 93: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1895
    - Page 97: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1896
    - Page 101: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1897
    - Page 105: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1898
    - Page 109: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1899
    - Page 113: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1900
    - Page 115-116: these pages are missing, and included the end of 1900 and the beginning of 1901
    - Page 119: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1902
    - Page 123: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1903
    - Page 125: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1904
    - Page 127: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1905
    - Page 131: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1906
    - Page 133: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1907
    - Page 134: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1908
    - Page 137: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1909
    - Page 139: A complete list of Indian relics found about Portland, Conn. and vicinity during the year 1911
    - Page 175: Notes
      Includes information about Indian relics found in the area, and some specific descriptions of found relics.
    - Page 198: Poem, The Story of An Arrowhead Translated, composed by John B. Sumner, Portland, Conn.
    - Page 205: Poem, A View from a Hilltop at Portland, Conn., composed by John B. Sumner, Portland, Conn.
    - Page 207: Sunset, composed by John B. Sumner, Portland, Conn., 1882
    - Page 209: April 9, 1905
      A description of Neff's findings that day.
    - Page 210: Journal of Henry D. Thoreau, March 19, 1842; Henry D. Thoreau Journal, March 28, 1859
      These appear to be copied passages from Thoreau's journal.